What was that?
（クルシュ･カルステン）何だと？
All right, I'll repeat myself one more time.
（ナツキ･スバル）
じゃあ もう一度言うぜ
I propose an alliance between the Emilia
and Crusch camps, on equal terms.
エミリア陣営とクルシュ陣営の
対等な条件での同盟
To that end, I'll provide the time and location
そのために こちらが
差し出す情報は―
of the White Whale's next appearance.
白鯨の出現時間と場所
それが俺の切れるカードだ
That's the one card I can play.
The Witch Cult?
（レム）魔女教？
Yeah, they're on the move
and they've set their sights on Emilia.
奴らが エミリアを狙って
動き出してる
Roswaal-sama feared that might happen as well.
確かに その可能性は
ロズワール様も危ぶまれていました
（スバル）
俺はそれを止めたい
でも戦力が足りないんだ
I want to stop them,
but I don't have the fighting strength.
I have to start negotiating now to pull some together.
これから なんとか交渉して
かき集めなきゃならない
Will you help me?
力を貸してくれるか
The White Whale?
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
白鯨…
（ヴィルヘルム）ハアー
Please forgive my indiscretion.
大変失礼をいたしました
私も まだまだ未熟ですな
I suppose I still have much to learn.
And?
それで？ 白鯨とは―
It is rather sudden that you
would bring up the White Whale.
またいささか
唐突な単語が出てきたな
Not at all.
そうでもねえさ
When we began this negotiation,
同盟を結ぶにあたって―
I mentioned the magic stones found
in Roswaal's domain, in Elior Forest.
こっちが提示した
ロズワールの領地にある―
エリオール大森林の魔鉱石
If sharing the mining rights is insufficient,
その採掘権の１部じゃ
割に合わないってんなら―
I need to offer something on top of that.
あと１歩 そっちの背中を
押さなきゃならないし―
Crusch-san, I'm certain that my information will aid
クルシュさん あんたが
計画している白鯨の討伐に―
俺の情報は絶対に役立つはずだ
in your plan to subjugate the White Whale.
Let me ask one thing, Natsuki Subaru.
（クルシュ）
１つ 考えを聞こう ナツキ･スバル
What gave you that idea?
その発想はどこから出てきた
That remark was not one you might
pass off as a baseless accusation.
言い掛かりでは済まされない
たぐいの発言だぞ
For these past few days,
ここ何日かで
いくつか引っ掛かったんだよ
some things have bothered me.
First, the increase in traffic
to and from your mansion.
まず 屋敷の出入りの多さだ
It's been just a bit excessive.
ちょっとばかし
人と物の出入りが過剰だ
Also, in the capital, I heard you've been
purchasing weapons and armor.
それから 武器と防具を―
クルシュさんが
買い集めてるってのも王都で聞いた
Plus...
おまけに―
If Crusch-sama's goal should be attained,
（ラッセル･フェロー）
このたびの クルシュ様の狙いが
なるのであれば―
I'm sure it would suit your
desires, Wilhelm-dono.
ヴィルヘルム殿にとっても
悲願となりましょう
You seemed to be planning something big.
（スバル）
クルシュさんが 何か
でかいことを企(たくら)んでるってことも
Of course, I can't prove it.
確証があるわけじゃないんだ
Maybe I only made the connection
近いうちに白鯨が現れるって
俺が知ってるから―
because I know the White Whale
will be appearing soon.
関連付けちまってる
だけかもしれねえが
I have another question, Natsuki Subaru.
（クルシュ）
もう１つ問おう ナツキ･スバル
On what grounds do you know
that the White Whale will appear?
卿(けい)が 白鯨が現れると知っている
その根拠は
This.
（スバル）これだよ
What in the world is this?
これは一体何だ？
The moment before that happened...
（スバル）あの時 あの直前
It's what you'd call a metia.
（スバル）
いわゆる ミーティアってやつでな
It tells me when and where
the White Whale will appear.
そいつが白鯨が現れる
時間と場所を教えてくれる
I find this a bit hard to believe...
にわかには信じ難いが
But I see that you are not lying.
ウソは言っていないな
I'm glad you think that, but are you sure
you want to believe me so easily?
その判断はありがたいけど―
いいのかよ そんなあっさり
Lies will get you nyowhere with Crusch-sama.
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
クルシュ様に
ウソは通用しにゃいの
She has the divine protection of wind-reading!
風見の加護がついてるからね
Uh, say what?
（スバル）ん… 何て？
When a person lies, a telling wind blows around them.
ウソ 偽りを口にする者のもとには
そういう風が吹くものだ
I can see that wind.
私には それが見える
No such thing was around you.
卿には それが一切なかった
Does that mean you'll agree to an alliance
なら 白鯨の情報をもとに―
in exchange for my information
on the White Whale?
同盟を認めてくれるって
ことでいいのか
You're getting ahead of yourself, Natsuki Subaru.
それは早計だ ナツキ･スバル
Whether I agree to it,
同盟を結ぶかどうかと―
and whether I believe you are separate matters.
その情報を信じる 信じないは
別個の問題だ
My decision will determine
事は 王選の―
the outcome of the royal selection,
if not the kingdom's very future.
あるいは 王国の未来を
左右する判断だ
It cannot be made lightly.
軽はずみには行えまい
Mind if I listen in on this lil' chat, too?
（アナスタシア･ホーシン）
そのお話 うちらも聞かせて
もらってええ？
Pardon us.
（ラッセル）失礼いたします
Anastasia Hoshin...
（クルシュ）
アナスタシア･ホーシン
ラッセル･フェロー
Russell Fellow?
Well, y'all asked us to come, and here ya are,
なんや 呼び出されたから
来たのに―
startin' without us.
先にお話進めてるなんて
ズルいやないの
You can hardly call that fair. Let us in on this.
うちらも混ぜたって
Was it Natsuki Subaru who asked you to come here?
呼び出されたということは
卿らを呼んだのはナツキ･スバルか
Well, to be exact, it was this gal he keeps with him.
正確には ここの
お付きの女の子にやね
I only heard the gist,
おおまかにしか
聞いてへんけど―
but if you're really plannin' to subjugate
the White Whale, I look forward to it!
白鯨の討伐 ホンマやったら
大いに期待するわ
For us business folk,
うちら 商人にとって―
whether the White Whale's around
is a life-or-death matter.
白鯨のおる おらんは
死活問題やから
Of course, our mercenary team will help y'all.
もちろん
うちの傭(よう)兵団も手 貸すよ
In addition to the White Whale, I'm interested
私は 白鯨の件も
そうなのですが―
in the concession that Natsuki-dono
ナツキ殿から提案された―
proposed of mining rights to the magic stones.
魔鉱石の採掘権の
割譲に興味がありまして
If the alliance is formed,
もし 同盟が結ばれれば
クルシュ様を通じて―
magic stones from pristine veins
will be distributed to the capital
through you, Crusch-sama.
手つかずの鉱脈の魔石が
王都に流れることになります
As the merchant guild's representative,
I cannot let the offer go unheard.
王都の商業組合の代表としては
聞き逃せません
Natsuki Subaru called you as well?
卿も ナツキ･スバルに？
I'll say it once more.
改めて言う
What I offer in return for the alliance is
同盟に際して
こっちから出せるのは―
a share in the magic stone mining rights
魔鉱石の採掘権の１部と
白鯨出現の時間と場所の情報
and information on when and where
the White Whale will appear.
In other words, the fuel needed
to subjugate the witchfiend
つまり 長いこと世界を
脅かしてきた魔獣の討伐
that's terrorized the world for so long!
その栄誉だ
If what I say makes no sense to you, forget I said it.
俺の言葉が的外れで―
意味がさっぱりってんなら
切り捨ててくれ
But if your goal and my wish align,
けど もし あんたの狙いと
俺の望みがかち合うなら―
then let's take down the White Whale!
白鯨を討伐しよう
Let's go on a hunt!
一狩りいこうぜ
ハア…
I still have several questions,
いくらか疑問の余地はあるが―
but it was brilliant of you to uncover my plans.
こちらの思惑を
見抜いたのは見事だった
Then...
それじゃあ
I have questions, as well as doubts.
（クルシュ）
疑問はある 疑念もある
Many things you say are unclear to me,
腑(ふ)に落ちない点も多く
即座にうなずくのは難しい
so I have difficulty agreeing immediately.
However...
だが―
I shall choose to trust your eyes
この状況を作った 卿の意気と
この目を信じることにしよう
and the spirit that led you to create this situation.
Then the deal is struck.
交渉は成立ですね
（スバル）ダアー
There were a few touch-and-go moments,
（ラッセル）
何度かひやひやさせられましたが
何よりです ナツキ殿
but I'm glad it worked out, Natsuki-dono.
I trust the promise we made prior
to the negotiation still stands.
交渉の前のお約束は 確かに
Yeah, you were a big help, Russell-san.
ああ 助かったよ ラッセルさん
Once the subjugation is complete,
I'll give you the metia.
討伐が済んだら
ミーティアはあんたに譲るさ
ハア… やはり根回ししていたか
So you did lay some groundwork before coming here.
I'm assuming you were waiting outside
the door for your moment to enter?
扉の前で 入る機会を
うかがっていたな？
いつ割り込むかは
うちら任せやったけどね
The timing of our interruption was up to us, though.
Well, as far as negotiations go, I guess that just passes?
まあ 交渉としては
ギリギリ及第点と違う？
Took you long enough!
遅(おせ)えんだよ
I thought you were never gonna enter!
最後まで入って
こねえんじゃねえかと思ったよ
When negotiatin', you gotta
make your move at the right time.
交渉には押し時ってのがあるんよ
Well, as you're gettin' ready
for the subjugation and such,
じゃあ 討伐の準備
そのほか もろもろ―
don't forget to patronize the Hoshin Company.
ホーシン商会を
ひいきにしたってな
You paved the way before negotiations began?
交渉以前に道は整えていた… か
You are surprisingly shrewd, Natsuki Subaru.
存外 食えない男だな
ナツキ･スバル
My preparation and review paid off, that's all.
（スバル）
予習復習が
うまくはまったってだけだよ
To be honest, I couldn't be more relieved.
ぶっちゃけ
心底ほっとしてるぜ 俺
Well, that's plain to see.
まあ それは見れば
分かるけどねー
アッハハハ ハハハ…
I guess we managed to save
face by staying in the capital.
何とか 王都に残った
面目は保てただろ レム
Right, Rem?
Yes, you are truly wonderful, Subaru-kun.
はい さすが
スバルくんはステキです
（ヴィルヘルム）スバル殿
Subaru-dono...
I thank you.
感謝を
Huh?
I offer you gratitude
我が主君―
equal to that which I offer to my lady,
Duchess Crusch Karsten.
クルシュ･カルステン公爵へ
捧(ささ)げるものと―
同等の感謝をあなたに
E-Er, that's, um...
あ… えーと その…
As perceptive as you are,
（ヴィルヘルム）
賢明なスバル殿は―
I am sure you're aware,
but if I may introduce myself...
すでに見抜いて
おいででしょうが 改めて
My family name is Astrea.
私の家名は アストレア
I took the former Sword Saint,
Theresia van Astrea, as my wife,
先代の剣聖―
テレシア･ヴァン･アストレアを
妻にめとり―
giving me the honor of the bloodline's lowest seat.
剣聖の家系の末席を汚した身
That is who I, Wilhelm van Astrea, am.
それが 私―
ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレアです
I thank you for so kindly granting this old man
妻を奪った
憎き魔獣を討つ機会を―
the opportunity to slay the loathsome
witchfiend that took my wife.
この老体に与えてくださる温情に
感謝を
S-Sure! Of course I knew that!
あ… ああ もちろん知ってたけど
I figured Crusch-san would accept
my offer, keeping that in mind—
当然 それ込みで―
クルシュさんが乗っかってくるって
思ってたわけで…
Natsuki Subaru...
ナツキ･スバル
The wind of untruth is blowing from you.
ウソの風が吹いているぞ 卿から
I get it now.
（スバル）なるほどな
You bought all the carriages for this,
これで竜車が
買い占められるから―
and that's why I had trouble
getting one back to the mansion.
屋敷に戻る足の確保に
手こずったわけだ
You're still awake?
（フェリックス）
まだ寝てなかったの？
As if I could sleep.
そんなわけにいくかよ
みんな 徹夜で準備してんのに
Everyone else is working through the night.
They have nyo choice.
（フェリックス）
しょうがにゃいの
時間ないんでしょ？
We have little time.
Yeah, the White Whale will appear tomorrow night,
ああ 白鯨が現れんのは
明日の夜
in the area around Flügel's Tree.
フリューゲルの大樹の周辺だ
So, given the travel time, we'll just barely make it.
だったら 移動の時間考えても
ギリギリなの
Besides, can't you see it in nyall their faces?
それに みんなの顔見て
気づかにゃい？
Nyot a single one is preparing unwillingly.
いやいや準備してる人なんて
１人もいにゃい
Everyone wants to be rid of the White Whale,
白鯨討伐は みんなの悲願だから
especially Old Man Wil.
特に ヴィル爺(じい)にとってはね
He said it took his wife...
（スバル）
奥さんを… って言ってたよな
Yeah.
He's been chasing after the White Whale all this time.
ヴィル爺は ずっと
白鯨を追いかけてきたから
Ever since it killed the former Sword Saint, his wife.
先代の剣聖 ヴィル爺の奥さんが
白鯨にやられてから ずっとね
The former Sword Saint...
先代の剣聖
Well, now you know,
（フェリックス）
まあ そういうことだから―
so you should stop worrying and get to sleep.
スバルきゅんは気にせず
とっとと寝ること
There's nyothing you can do to help
どうせ 物資の手配とか
編成とか―
with supply distribution or organization, anyway.
スバルきゅんにできることは
何もにゃいんだし
Even if that's true,
確かにそうかも知れねえけど
ストレートに言うな
that doesn't mean you have to say it!
I'm supposed to pick one of these?
（スバル）
好きな子 選べって言われてもよ
What is it nyow? You don't like them?
にゃにさ
気に入らないっていうの？
It's not that!
（スバル）
違くて 貸してくれるのは
うれしいんだけど―
I'm glad you're letting me borrow one,
but I have no idea what makes one good!
よしあしなんて
ぶっちゃけ分かんねえよ
Do I look like a veteran who's studied nothing
but land dragons for decades or some—
俺が 地竜一筋十数年の
ベテランにでも見えるかって…
お前 ひょっとして この間の…
Are you that one from...
Looks like this is the one.
どうも こいつがよさそうだな
I am surprised.
驚きました
That land dragon is a breed known
for its extreme pride.
この地竜 気位が高いことで
有名な種類だと思ったんですけど
Ferris, I'll take this one.
フェリス こいつにする
一目ぼれだ
It's love at first sight!
Sure thing.
はいはーい
But don't say, "Love at first sight."
でも レムちゃんがすねてるから
一目ぼれとか言わない
You're making Rem-chan all pouty!
I'm not pouty!
別にすねてませんよ
ちゃんと仲よくします
I'll be nice to it! I can do it!
できます
Huh!? Wha...
My lady was tellin' me about you.
（リカード･ウェルキン）
お嬢から話は聞いとるわ
You're the star of this little show, aren't ya?
兄ちゃんが
今日の立て役者なんやろ？
That logo...
（スバル）
その屋号に カララギ弁の獣人…
And a Kararagi accent from a beastman...
Then, you're with Anastasia?
ってことは アナスタシアの
What, you knew?
なんや 知っとったんか？
ワイは団長のリカード言うねん
I'm Ricardo, head of her mercenary team.
Nice to meet you, too, lil' lady!
そっちの嬢ちゃんも
よろしゅうな！
Keep it down! Also, you're huge!
うるせえし でけえよ
首がもげるだろ
You'll snap my neck!
Hey! My lady!
おお お嬢
（スバル）あ… イッテ…
Whoa, hey!
Ow...
クソー…
So that is the pride of Anastasia Hoshin,
the Iron Fang.
（クルシュ）
あれがアナスタシア･
ホーシンが誇る 鉄の牙か
I see.
なるほど つわものぞろいのようだ
They all look quite strong.
Did you rest well last night?
昨晩は休めたか？
I nearly died a second ago...
今 危うく死にかけたよ
Oh, so I guess you're fighting too?
…て クルシュさんも
やっぱり戦うんだな
You think I am capable
イスに腰かけて―
of sitting in a chair, waiting for good news?
ただ吉報を待つことが
私にできると思うか？
If anything, I'm much more surprised
you are participating.
むしろ 卿の参戦のほうが意外だ
Can you fight?
卿は戦えるのか？
Nope, I can't.
戦えねえよ
ただ 戦力としてはアレだが―
But even if I can't fight,
I think this human will prove pretty
useful against the White Whale.
白鯨相手なら 俺って人間が
割と役に立つ と思う
I must ask... On what grounds?
聞こう その根拠は
I'm not all that happy about it myself,
あんまし俺自身も
うれしくねえんだが―
but it seems there's something
about me that attracts witchfiends.
どうも俺って 魔獣を
引き寄せる体質らしくてさ
What?
何だと？
It is true.
本当です
Thanks to that attribute, Subaru-kun
has previously saved my life.
レムは前に そのおかげで
スバルくんに助けられたんです
So, on the land dragon I'm borrowing,
（スバル）
だから 借りた地竜で―
I'll run around under White Whale's nose
and draw its attention,
俺が白鯨の鼻先を駆け回って
注意を引きつけて―
while you guys launch an all-out attack!
その隙に
総攻撃を入れてもらう
That's the tactic I'd recommend, anyway.
…ってのが 俺の
オススメ戦術なんだけど
Under the White Whale's... nose?
白鯨の… 鼻先を？
Shockingly, I sense no lies in that statement.
驚くべきことに
ウソの気配はないのだな
I never thought
昨日からの半日で―
I would doubt my divine protection
as often as I have in the past half day.
こう何度も 自分の加護を
疑う機会がくるとは思わなんだ
They're here.
来たか
Crusch-sama, we have arrived.
（コンウッド･メラハウ）
クルシュ様
参上いたしてございます
Is this boy...
そちらの彼が？
Yes, he is.
ああ そうだ
Thank you, young man.
（コンウッド）ありがとう 少年
Huh?
Thanks to you, our wish may come true.
君のおかげで 我々の悲願がかなう
これほどうれしいことはない
We could not be happier.
Thank you.
ありがとう
It seems all of them have a history
with the White Whale.
（レム）
全員 白鯨に縁のある方
なのでしょうね
Then, they're like Wilhelm-san?
ってことは
ヴィルヘルムさんと似たような？
Yes,
ああ 一線を退いていた者たちも
多かったがな
many are men who have retired
from the front lines.
They have joined our subjugation force
at Wilhelm's invitation.
ヴィルヘルムの呼びかけで
こたびの討伐隊に加わった者たちだ
Their morale and experience
士気と練度は―
is comparable to those of the capital's active knights.
現役の王国騎士団にも
見劣りしまい
Crusch-sama, it's time.
クルシュ様 そろそろ
Right.
Four hundred years.
400年だ
Since the White Whale, created by the Witch of Envy,
嫉妬の魔女が
生み出した白鯨が―
made the world its hunting ground,
世界を狩り場とし わがもの顔で
弱者を蹂躙(じゅうりん)しながら―
trampling the weak and dominating
the land as if it were its owner,
跋扈(ばっこ)するようになって
400年が過ぎた
four hundred years have passed.
Countless lives have been lost in that time.
その月日で奪われた命は
数えきれない
Given its fog's unscrupulous nature, as well,
その霧の性質の
悪辣(あくらつ)さも相まって―
the number of graves we cannot even
inscribe with names will only rise.
銘すら残すことのできない
墓碑の数は 増えるばかりだ
But those days of sitting idle end today!
だが その無為の日々は
今日をもって終わる
Today, those of us here will end it!
ここにいる
我らが終わらせる
We shall strike down the White Whale,
and stop further tragedy!
白鯨を討ち
あまたの悲しみを終わらせよう
We shall give the sorrow,
which was never allowed to come to pass,
悲しみにすら
たどり着けなかった悲しみに―
a chance to shed overdue tears!
正しく 涙の機会を与えよう
We move out!
出陣する！
Our destination is Flügel's Tree,
on the Lifaus Highway.
場所はリーファウス街道
フリューゲルの大樹
Tonight, we shall slay the White Whale
with our own hands!
こよい 我らの手で―
白鯨を討つ！
I'm Mimi! Glad to know ya!
（ミミ･パールバトン）
ミミなのだ よろしく！
My name's Hetaro. Nice to meet you.
（ヘータロー･パールバトン）
ヘータローです
よろしくお願いします
Yep, nice to meet you.
おお よろしく
Anyway, not that I doubted it, but...
しかし 疑ってたわけじゃ
ないんだけど―
お前 本当に副団長だったんだな
You really are the second-in-command, huh?
Huh? Have we met somewhere before?
んー？ お兄さん
ミミとどっかで会った？
Hmm... I totally can't remember at all!
んん… 思い出せない感じが
尋常じゃない
C-Come on, Sis,
ちょ ちょっとお姉ちゃん
ちゃんと乗って
you have to sit up properly.
Totally can't...
（ミミ）尋常じゃない
Don't worry about it. Just talking to myself.
気にすんな こっちの話だ
I'm Natsuki Subaru.
ナツキ･スバルだ
So you two are brother and sister, huh?
お姉ちゃんってことは
お前ら 姉弟(きょうだい)か？
Yes, my big sister and I will do our—
はい お姉ちゃんと２人 頑張り…
When Mimi and Hetaro are together,
we're the strongest!
ミミとヘータローがそろえば
最強！
And the captain's also here,
so we're the super strongest!
団長もいるし 超最強！ ヘヘヘ
Uh, my sister and the captain tend to be a little rash,
えーっと お姉ちゃんと団長は
よく先走っちゃうんで―
Strongest! Strongest! Super strongest!
so I usually give the orders.
僕が指示を出したり
I see...
そうか 苦労がしのばれるな
Must be rough...
What's the matter, bro? Ya look awful gloomy!
（リカード）
なんや 兄ちゃん
シケたツラしとるの
Whose fault is that?
（スバル）誰のせいだ
A captain shouldn't make trouble for his men.
団長が部下に
迷惑かけてんじゃねえよ
Hey, that's a nice land dragon ya got there.
おっ いい地竜乗っとるやないか
Hey!
おい！
Is it?
そうなのか？
I borrowed this one because
it seemed to like me, but...
なんか 懐いてくれたから
こいつを借りたんだが…
Come to think of it,
そういや あんたらは
また変わったのに乗ってるな
the things you guys ride look kinda bizarre.
They're called rigers.
ライガー言うねん
But ya don't see 'em too often in these parts.
こっちじゃ あんまり
見かけんかもなあ
They ain't as strong as land dragons,
力じゃ 地竜に負けやけど
身軽さは段違いや
but they're much more agile.
If it comes to a brawl against the Whale,
鯨退治で乱戦になったら
独壇場やから よー見とき
that's where they really shine, so watch close.
Shouldn't you have had land dragons pull the cargo, then?
（スバル）
だったら 荷物の運搬は―
地竜に任せたほうが
よかったんじゃねえの？
We've gotta manage our luggage on our own.
自分らの荷物ぐらい
自分らで管理せんとなあ
If ya think the White Whale's our only enemy,
白鯨ばっかが敵やと思うとると
足元すくわれかねんからな
you'll get the rug pulled out from under ya.
Ain't no guarantee we won't run
into thieves on the road, after all.
道中 盗賊やらに
絡まれんとも限らんしなあ
If anyone's got the guts to take on
a fully armed group like this,
（スバル）
こんな完全武装の一団を襲う
勇気があるんなら―
they wouldn't settle for being thieves.
盗賊なんてやってねえだろ
Good point!
そら そうやな
アッハハハハハハ…
It looks like Ricardo-sama is trying to ease everyone's nerves.
（レム）リカード様―
ああして 皆さんの緊張を
ほぐして回ってるみたいですね
Subaru-kun?
スバルくん？
I thought I'd prepared myself for this.
覚悟決まったはずなんだがな
目指せ英雄って言っても―
You can tell the hero inside to awaken,
but it really isn't as easy as it sounds.
なかなか きついもんだぜ
まったく
It's huge!
でっけーなあ
You sound happy, Subaru-kun.
うれしそうですね スバルくん
（スバル）イッヒヒ
Oh, looks like people have carved
their names into the trunk.
あっ でも 幹に
誰かの名前が彫ってあんなー
We aren't on some field trip.
修学旅行じゃあるまいし
マナーがなってねえよ マナーが
That's just bad manners...
Rem, get me a chisel!
レム 彫刻刀を貸してくれ
Even you should know that will
get you in trouble, Subaru-kun.
いくらスバルくんでも―
そんなことしたら
怒りますし 怒られますよ
With me, for starters.
So the White Whale is coming here?
ここに白鯨が来るんですね
Honestly, I am opposed to
本当はレムは反対なんです
using the witch's scent to draw
the White Whale here.
魔女の残り香で
白鯨を引き寄せるなんて―
It's too dangerous.
危険すぎます
I'll use whatever I can.
使えるもんは何でも使う
よっと
If it gives us even a slightly better
chance of winning, it's worth it.
それで勝率がコンマでも
上がるってんなら もうけもんだ
For a guy who lacks in every way like me,
足りないとこだらけの俺は―
this is the only way to make up for that.
そうでもしなきゃ
遅れが取り戻せねえ
You are wonderful, Subaru-kun.
スバルくんはステキです
（レム）
そのミーティアが
白鯨の存在を知らせてくれる
That metia will tell you when
the White Whale is coming?
Yeah,
（スバル）
ああ 時間になったら
鳴るようになってる
I set it to make noise when it's time.
To be honest, without this—
ぶっちゃけ これなしだと…
That's a lie.
（レム）ウソですよね
Wh-Why're ya sayin' that!?
な… 何を言い出しますのん？
If it's a lie, how d'ya think I'm gonna...
これがウソなら
ワイはどぎゃんして…
You're speaking in something
like the Kararagi dialect.
（レム）
カララギ弁のような
何かになってますし―
It doesn't suit you at all.
スバルくんには似合いませんよ
No, no, no! I mean, there's no way I could be lying!
（スバル）
いやいやいやいや 実際
これがウソとかありえねえだろ
Even Crusch-san said—
クルシュさんたちだってさ…
It's all right, Subaru-kun.
（レム）
いいんですよ スバルくん
I can always tell when you're lying.
スバルくんが
ウソをついていることぐらい―
レムには分かります
そのウソの理由が
話せないでいることも 分かります
I also know that you cannot tell me why you do so.
So there is no need to convince me
だから 信じさせようだとか
ウソで丸め込もうだとか―
or wrap everything in lies,
or try to take the blame on yourself like that.
そんな風に
自分を追い詰めたりする必要―
どこにもないんですよ
Because...
だってレムは スバルくんを
丸ごと信じていますから
I have complete faith in you, Subaru-kun.
Man!
Looking up at this huge tree sure fires you up, huh?
やっぱりでっかい木を見上げると
テンション上がるなー！
Yes, it does.
はい そうですね
I'm gonna have to stare at it for a long time, or I'll never relax!
（スバル）
これはしばらく見上げてないと
気分 落ち着かないわー
I won't be able to look down for a while!
しばらく 下とか見れないわー
Yes, you're right.
はい そうですね
I should say "thank you" instead
of "sorry" right now, huh?
ごめんより
ありがとうだよな
こういう時は
You're welcome.
（レム）
どういたしまして ですよ
Besides, I am far more grateful to you, Subaru-kun.
それに レムのほうが
ずっとずっと―
スバルくんに
感謝しているんですから
おあいこです
So we're even.
Uh...
（スバル）
あの ヴィルヘルムさん
Wilhelm-san?
I heard a bit of the story from Ferris.
フェリスから
ちょこっと聞きました
奥さんの敵である白鯨を
ずっと追いかけてきたって
That you've been seeking revenge on
the Whale ever since it took your wife.
Please forget that.
（ヴィルヘルム）お忘れください
It was all time idly spent in an old man's delusions.
老木のつまらぬ妄執(もうしゅう)と
無為に過ごした時間です
You truly love your wife, do you not?
奥様を愛していらっしゃるんですね
Yes, I love my wife.
ええ 妻を愛しております
More than anyone.
誰よりも
And no matter how much time passes.
どれほど時間が過ぎようとも
妻は 花をめでるのが
好きな女性でした
My wife was a woman who loved to look at flowers.
She never wished to wield a sword,
剣を振ることを好まず
しかし 誰よりも剣に愛された
but the sword loved her more than anyone.
With no choice but to live for the sword,
剣に生きることしか許されず―
my wife accepted her fate.
妻もまた その運命を
受け入れておりました
When I married her, I took it from her,
私は 彼女から剣を奪い
剣聖の名を捨てさせ 妻とした
forcing her to abandon the title of "Sword Saint."
But the sword would not allow her to do that.
ですが 剣は彼女を
許してなどいなかった
Subaru-dono, I thank you again.
スバル殿 改めて感謝を
In this battle, I can find answers in my own sword.
この戦いで 私は私の剣に
答えを見つけられる
And perhaps I shall finally be
able to visit my wife's grave.
妻の墓前にも やっと
足を向けることができましょう
At last, I can go and see her.
やっと 妻に
会いに行くことができる
Let's work together to beat the
hell out of that damn whale.
力を合わせて あの鯨野郎を
ぶちのめしてやりましょう
I'll give it everything I've got too.
俺も全力で手伝いますから
Only a short time remains.
定刻まで あとわずかだな
Troops, be on guard!
総員 警戒！
I don't see it...
（隊員Ａ）
見当たらないぞ
（クルシュ）こないか
It isn't coming?
Is that...
（隊員Ｂ）あれは！
総員！
Troops—
Let him have it!
ぶちかませー！
Al Huma!
アルヒューマ！
Troops! Follow those two fools!
総員 あのバカどもに続けー！
Battle Against the  White Whale